<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Read.Write.Code</title>
    <link>https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/tags/stupidity/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Read.Write.Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rdwrcode&#34;&gt;rdwrcode&lt;/a&gt; 2016. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/tags/stupidity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dietrich Bonhoeffer on stupidity</title>
      <link>https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/post/dietrich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 08:40:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/post/dietrich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This part is an excerpt from Letters and Papers from Prison by Dietrich Bonhoeffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stupidity is a more dangerous enemy of the good than malice. One may protest against evil; it can be exposed and, if need be, prevented by use of force. Evil always carries within itself the germ of its own subversion in that it leaves behind in human beings at least a sense of unease. Against stupidity we are defenseless. Neither protests nor the use of force accomplish anything here; reasons fall on deaf ears; facts that contradict one’s prejudgment simply need not be believed – in such moments the stupid person even becomes critical – and when facts are irrefutable they are just pushed aside as inconsequential, as incidental. In all this the stupid person, in contrast to the malicious one, is utterly self satisfied and, being easily irritated, becomes dangerous by going on the attack. For that reason, greater caution is called for when dealing with a stupid person than with a malicious one. Never again will we try to persuade the stupid person with reasons, for it is senseless and dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to know how to get the better of stupidity, we must seek to understand, its nature. This much is certain, that it is in essence not an intellectual defect but a human one. There are human beings who are of remarkably agile intellect yet stupid, and others who are intellectually quite dull yet anything but stupid. We discover this to our surprise in particular situations. The impression one gains is not so much that stupidity is a congenital defect but that, under certain circumstances, people are made stupid or that they allow this to happen to them. We note further that people who have isolated themselves from others or who live in solitude manifest this defect less frequently than individuals or groups of people inclined or condemned to sociability. And so it would seem that stupidity is perhaps less a psychological than a sociological problem. It is a particular form of the impact of historical circumstances on human beings, a psychological concomitant of certain external conditions. Upon closer observation, it becomes apparent that every strong upsurge of power in the public sphere, be it of a political or a religious nature, infects a large part of humankind with stupidity. It would even seem that this is virtually a sociological-psychological law. The power of the one needs the stupidity of the other. The process at work here is not that particular human capacities, for instance, the intellect, suddenly atrophy or fail. Instead, it seems that under the overwhelming impact of rising power, humans are deprived of their inner independence and, more or less consciously, give up establishing an autonomous position toward the emerging circumstances. The fact that the stupid person is often stubborn must not blind us to the fact that he is not independent. In conversation with him, one virtually feels that one is dealing not at all with him as a person, but with slogans, catchwords, and the like that have taken possession of him. He is under a spell, blinded, misused, and abused in his very being. Having thus become a mindless tool, the stupid person will also be capable of any evil and at the same time incapable of seeing that it is evil. This is where the danger of diabolical misuse lurk, for it is this that can once and for all destroy human beings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet at this very point it becomes quite clear that only an act of liberation, not instruction, can overcome stupidity. Here we must come to terms with the fact that in most cases a genuine internal liberation becomes possible only when external liberation has preceded it. Until then we must abandon all attempts to convince the stupid person. This state of affairs explains why in such circumstances our attempts to know what “the people” really think are in vain and why, under these circumstances, this question is so irrelevant for the person who is thinking and acting responsibly. The word of the Bible that the fear of God is the beginning of wisdom declares that the internal liberation of human beings to live the responsible life before God is the only genuine way to overcome stupidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these thoughts about stupidity also offer consolation in that they utterly forbid us to consider the majority of people to be stupid in every circumstance. It really will depend on whether those in power expect more from peoples’ stupidity than from their inner independence and wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;对一个好人而言，愚蠢是比邪恶更危险的敌人。人们可以抗议邪恶，揭露邪恶，如果必要，可以用武力阻止它。邪恶总是携带着自毁的病毒，这至少让人们觉得不自在。而面对愚蠢，我们无从抵抗。抗议或者武力没有什么用处。没处说理，和成见相矛盾的事实没人相信，这种时候愚蠢的人变得更加重要。而当事实无可辩驳时，这些事实竟然被视为无足轻重或偶然巧合而被弃之不用。在这样的情况下，相对于恶人，愚人沉浸于自我满足、容易被激怒。愚蠢的人甚至开始攻击而变得更加危险。因此对付愚蠢要比对付邪恶更加小心。我们再不要试图用道理劝说愚蠢的人，因为这样是不明智和危险的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;如果想要知道怎样更好地应对愚蠢，我们必须理解它的本性。有一点是肯定的，愚蠢根本不是智力缺陷而是人性的缺陷。总有一些相当聪颖的人却很愚蠢，另一些人智力平平也一样愚蠢。我们会在些特别的情况下吃惊地发现这一点。我们得到的印象是愚蠢不是生理缺陷，人们总是被人愚弄或者允许自己愚蠢。更进一步，那些喜欢扎堆的人比离群索居的人比更容易感染愚蠢。因此愚蠢是个社会问题甚于心理问题。愚蠢是历史环境对人影响的一种特别形式，某些外部条件的自然心理产物。如果更仔细地观察，任何势力无论是政治或宗教，在公共领域崛起之时，会用愚蠢感染相当多的人。而这完全可以成为一个社会心理原理。一方的权力需要另一方的愚蠢。这里起作用的过程不是人类的特殊能力比如智力突然萎缩或失灵。相反，在这种崛起势力的超强影响之下，人们有意无意地失去自身的独立性，放弃了针对这一新情况的自主地位。愚蠢的人通常是倔强的这一事实不应让我们忽视他们已经不再独立。通过和他们交谈，我们可以发现我们不是在和一个正常人打交道，而是和一个已经被口号、流行语攫取的人打交道。他已然着魔，盲目地滥用自己。如此，一个愚蠢的人已经变成失去心智的工具，可以做出任何邪恶的事而同时对邪恶视而不见。这就是愚蠢的邪恶危险之处，它可以一次彻底毁灭人类。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>