<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Read.Write.Code</title>
    <link>https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/tags/science/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Read.Write.Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rdwrcode&#34;&gt;rdwrcode&lt;/a&gt; 2016. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>davidwhattodo</title>
      <link>https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/post/davidwhattodo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 09:17:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/post/davidwhattodo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;last Renaissance -&amp;gt; from the mid-1500s to mid-1600s, Galileo, Hobbes, Descartes, Locke, Leibniz and Newton -&amp;gt; Scientific revolution -&amp;gt; the Enlightenment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it requires intellectual courage to be open to new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the greater danger for most of us lies not in setting our aim too high and falling short; but in setting our aim too low, and achieving our mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dare to fail?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vera rubin</title>
      <link>https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/post/verarubin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 16:25:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rdwrcode.github.io/b/post/verarubin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vera Rubin is an astronomer. She discovered the presence of dark matter in galaxies by observing their rotation. Her groundbreaking observations demonstrated that the rotation of galaxies is faster, especially in their outskirts, than what is expected from the gravitational pull of all of their normal, luminous mass (stars, gas, etc). This pioneering observation revealed that a large part of the mass of galaxies is in the form of dark matter. &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; we have peered into a new world and have seen that it is more mysterious and more complex than we had imagined.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;发现宇宙暗物质存在证据的天文学家Vera Rubin在今年圣诞去世，享年88岁。她通过观测星系的旋转，发现星系边缘的运动要比其在星系全部正常明亮物质（包括星体、星云等）的引力作用所应有的旋转快。这一先驱性的发现揭示了星系中存在大量暗物质，推进了人类对宇宙空间的认识。用她自己的话，（暗物质让）我们看到了一个全新的世界，远比我们所能想象的更神秘、更复杂。“&amp;hellip; we have peered into a new world and have seen that it is more mysterious and more complex than we had imagined.&amp;rdquo; （摘自Bright Galaxies, Dark Matters by Vera Rubin）。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1996年五月，Vera在加州伯克利的毕业典礼上这样说道：”&amp;hellip;在这样的时刻，我好奇你们是否意识到自己的过去其实很悠久，而你们的未来更加绵长。我记得一则我家人喜欢的Peanuts漫画。Lucy对Charlie Brown说，‘海洋上有很多船，有些船载着乘客。这些乘客喜欢做的一件事是坐在甲板上看海。有些乘客喜欢向前看，这样他们看到自己前往何处。有些人喜欢向后看，看自己去过的地方。’然后Lucy问，‘在生活这艘船上，你要怎样摆放你的椅子？’Charlie Brown回答，‘我的椅子还没撑开。’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vera的发现足以让她获得诺贝尔奖。有人这样说，1948年没有颁诺贝尔和平奖，大家普遍认为那是因为甘地在那年去世。2017年或许可以不颁诺贝尔物理奖，因为Vera Rubin今年去世了。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>